Joel Sprinkle

Suite 2, 165 Huron Ave. N. Ottawa, ON K1Y 0W5 Email: sprinklej@gmail.com, joel.sprinkle@carleton.ca

Phone: (613) 883-7208

Summary

Experience Building software in a team environment
Experience working with small business networks: modems, routers, network switches
Strong problem solving skills in solving technical issues with software and/or hardware
Ability to communicate with clients in a nontechnical way
Ability to take initiative and work in a team environment

Skills

Languages: AutoHotKey, C, C++, Java, JavaScript, and Python Completed Codecademy.com courses: HTML & CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and Ruby Can work in Linux, Mac and Windows Operating Systems

Related Work Experience

Cote Business Systems 2011 - 2014

IT Consultant duties

Onsite IT consulting: diagnosing hardware failures, upgrading hardware and software, network setup, and setting up new hardware.

Remote IT consulting: help clients with email/Outlook, login issues, installing new software, and removing adware.

Worked onsite for Cineplex Odeon as the eyes, ears, and hands of the remote IT team.

Programmed scripts to improve user workflows, individually and in a team.

Web design, in PHP using the Codelgniter framework.

Other Work Experience

The Wellington Diner 2015 - Present

Line Cook

Main duties: working on the line, doing prep-work, opening and closing the line, and cleaning the line and equipment.

Original Joe's Restaurant & Bar

2005 - 2011

Kitchen Manager, 2008 - 2011

Main duties: Skilled in all regular kitchen duties, responsible for scheduling, placing grocery orders, managing inventory, hiring and training new staff, leading team meetings.

Other roles: Helped setup new franchise locations, catering private events.

Line Cook, 2005 - 2008

Main duties: Working at all stations - grill, salads and pastas, plating food, expediting food and ensuring quality. Opening and closing the line. Cleaning the line and equipment.

Joel Sprinkle

Suite 2, 165 Huron Ave. N. Ottawa, ON K1Y 0W5 Email: sprinklej@gmail.com, joel.sprinkle@carleton.ca

Phone: (613) 883-7208

Education and Honours

Carleton University 2014 - 2017

Graduated with High Distinction – Bachelor of Computer Science Honours, Software Engineering Stream Carleton University Entrance Scholarship (2014)
Henry Marshall Tory Scholarship (2015)
Chalmers Jack MacKenzie Scholarship (2016)
Deans' Honour List (2015, 2016)

MacEwan University 2011 - 2014

Major: Computer Science Minor: Earth Sciences

Other

Golden Key International Honour Society

I am a member of the Golden Key Society, which has chapters around the world and offers memberships to students in the top 15% of their class.